<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="app_name">My Video Games</string>
    <string name="hello_world">Hello world!</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="add_game">Add New Game</string>
    <string name="video_game_api_key">9be0ead91d814eeb64cc5fb0da481ce726a22400</string>

    <!-- Obtained from:       http://electronics.howstuffworks.com/video-game6.htm       Let's  hope it's all legit! -->
    <string-array name="video_game_facts">
        <item>The Sega Dreamcast was the first console to implement online play over a phone line, calling the system Sega Net.</item>
        <item>The Microsoft Xbox was the first video game system to provide full support for HDTV.</item>
        <item>The Magnavox Odyssey, released in 1972, contained 40 transistors and no microprocessor. The Pentium 4 microprocessor contains 42 million transistors on the chip itself!</item>
        <item>The PlayStation 2 was the first system to have graphics capability better than that of the leading-edge personal computer at the time of its release.</item>
        <item>The Nintendo N64 marked the first time that computer graphics workstation manufacturer Silicon Graphics Inc. (SGI) developed game hardware technology.</item>
        <item>While the original Atari Football game was first created in 1973, it wasn\'t released until 1978. It was delayed because the game couldn\'t scroll the screen -- players couldn\'t move beyond the area shown on the monitor. When the game was finally released, it became the first game to utilize scrolling, a key part of many games today.</item>
        <item>The Atari Pong video game console was the No. 1 selling item for the holiday season in 1975.</item>
        <item>The PlayStation 2 was the first video game system to use DVD technology.</item>
        <item>On the original Magnavox Odyssey, players had to keep score themselves because the machine couldn\'t.</item>
        <item>The Nintendo GameCube\'s proprietary disc held 1.5 gigabytes of data -- 190 times more than what an N64 game cartridge could hold.</item>
        <item>On the market from 1991 till 2004, the SNK NeoGeo AES has tied the Atari 2600 (1977-1990) as the longest supported gaming console in history.</item>
        <item>The Sega Genesis featured a version of the same Motorola processor that powered the original Apple Macintosh computer.</item>
        <item>Mattel\'s Intellivison system, introduced in 1980, featured an add-on called "PlayCable," which delivered games by cable TV.</item>
        <item>Nintendo\'s Game Boy was the most successful game system ever, with more than 100 million units sold worldwide.</item>
        <item>The word atari comes from the ancient Japanese game of Go and means "you are about to be engulfed." Technically, it is the word used by a player to inform his opponent that he is about to lose, similar to "check" in chess.</item>
        <item>In the 1980s, a service called Gameline allowed users to download games to the Atari 2600 over regular phone lines. It was not a success, but did form part of the foundation for America Online, the world\'s largest Internet service provider.</item>
        <item>The first color portable video game system was the Atari Lynx, introduced in 1989 and priced at $149.</item>
        <item>Introduced in 1993, the 3DO was the first video game system to be based entirely on CD technology</item>
        <item>The Sony PlayStation was originally intended as a CD add-on to the Super Nintendo. When licensing problems and other issues arose, Sony decided to develop the PlayStation as a machine of its own.</item>

    </string-array>

</resources>
